So,
how surprised are you to be sitting in
this role? Go, you flash back to like
November. It's kind of a quick rise to
get to this spot. What do you What do
you think?
>> Uh, sure. I think um,
you know, I don't know, surprised. You
you feel like, uh, every step along the
way you prepare for these opportunities
and, uh, surprise may not be the exact
feeling. And it might be grateful, you
know, um, incredibly encouraged and
motivated based on, you know, what I've
kind of seen over the past month of of
DQ's belief and and building me up. Man,
from the first day I got here, I have
felt a very specific development plan
for me. Um, whether it's getting to call
plays and practice at at different
points along the way, whether it's uh
getting to present in front of the team,
opportunities like that. So, um, you
know, I don't know if surprise the right
word, but, uh, incredibly grateful and
and and thankful to be here.
>> Obviously, you only you were a coach for
two years, but you have the playing
experience. So, how much did playing in
the different offenses and just playing
quarterback in the NFL prepare you to be
in this spot at this point?
>> Sure. I think um I've been very
fortunate to be around a lot of great
coaches, you know, like u every step of
the way, whether it was high school,
whether it was college, whether it was
in the NFL, the a lot of the men that
I've looked up to in my life have been
um fantastic coaches, whether it's a
teacher, whether it's a connector,
whether it's a developer. And so, uh,
you know, once I got to the NFL level as
a player,
you know, I that that flame was kind of
lit for me that that I wanted to be the
guy, you know, as close as you can to
calling a play in the huddle, you know,
getting to call the plays into the
quarterback is is the next closest thing
as as one of the play callers. So, I've
always had uh aspirations for this and
really excited to to get it going.
Um, I know you've said that you've sort
of always wanted to be a coach after
your playing days. Was play calling a
piece that was always really important
to you? And, you know, when did if so,
when did it become a
>> That's a great question. Um, I've just
seen the difference it can make. You
know, I I've I've seen the difference uh
at different stops in my career of
getting to see different styles,
different play callers, different
innovators, and and it's really
important um you know, when you're
creating a game plan, when you're
developing players, putting them in the
best position to succeed that you know
how important the play calling role is.
So, kind of like I mentioned um for
John, like
it's as close as you can get to to
calling the play in the huddle and
actually being the guy receiving the
snap and and now developing that and and
helping get our group to the best
collective outcome is is what really
excites me.
>> Then, having, like you said, been with
so many coaches, how do how do you
envision your offense and how much will
you take from them as you sort of build
this out?
I think every step along the way, uh,
I've gotten to learn something. And as
we go forward, our staff, you know, our
our collective staff of 12 or 13
coaches, um, we get to kind of build it
up from the studs around what Jaden and
Ter, you know, Terry and Larry and all
these guys do really well to, um, you
know, put them in the best position to
be successful. And that's what's
exciting with our staff even pulling
from all these different experiences,
new coaches coming in who have, you
know, backed up Tom Brady and Aaron
Rogers and coaches who have been around
Drew Brees and develop young
quarterbacks and um being able to pull
the collective so that we can all
collaborate together and make this the
best possible thing is what's uh what's
really stimulating right now.
>> Hey, coach. Um, one thing Dan mentioned
was that he anticipates Jaden will be
under center a little bit more next
year. I wonder why you thought that was
important going forward.
>> Yeah, I think um, you know, it opens up
right the uh, you know, some different
schemes in the run game. Some things
that I believe in. It opens up different
uh, play actions and keepers and getting
them on the perimeter in different ways.
Um, you know, I think there's a level of
communication that happens under center.
I think there's just there's different
ways to go about things and it's
something that uh I'm convicted about
that um with his skill set, his
fundamentals, the things that we
absolutely loved about him when he first
got here still ring true and and as we
grow and develop um you know, I think a
lot of teams that you saw even playing
deep into the playoffs, you know, it was
something that was a foundation of of
what they did and and I think um you
know, that is something that we will
like to implement with him and and get
him in that position.
>> You've been credited with calling the
shot to Crowder to beat the Eagles in
24. And I just wonder what whether it
was the obvious film work you did, the
study you did, the personnel you knew,
understood, time, score, everything that
led you to believe that shot could work.
>> Sure. Um, you know, there's so much that
goes into one play of a, you know, say
you get 65 plays in a game and, um, that
was a situation that, uh, I had been a
part of previously in a different
organization that, um, a play that I had
strong conviction about in April of that
year and May and June. Uh there were
different experiences for Jaden along
the way that you know he didn't read it
exactly how we taught it the first time.
Then he learned from it the second time.
Then it came up a different way in
practice that week. And then um you know
the the practice execution became the
game reality from that week. And and he
uh he has a
um a really kind of he's got a gift when
you teach him something the first time
it just absorbs in there. So, um, you
know, I wouldn't say that that was just
me or any any any part of that. Um, you
know, there's a whole collective group
that goes into kind of creating one play
that comes up on a Sunday, Thursday,
Monday, you know. So,
>> coach, you've obviously worked with
Jaden since he got here, and you guys
have a pretty tight-knit relationship.
How would you describe your connection
with him that you've built over the last
two years, and what was his reaction
when you got this role?
Yeah, I think um you know that's one of
the best parts for me is that we have
two years worth of relationships already
built up. There's already deposits in
that bank that um you know we can pull
from. I if if we're talking about hey
what does he do well? What are we
building now? A lot of those
conversations have been had over the
last two years. Um so it's not starting
exactly from square one. and and I think
um as much as we can, we're going to
keep some continuity of of the way he,
you know, he's called things and and
then, you know, we got to build on it.
And uh I'm really excited to, you know,
just continue to challenge him, you
know, pull the best out of what he does
and help him grow. um because you know
we all know as as he goes this this
group will go and uh it's really an
exciting challenge and opportunity to to
just get him to his best.
>> And you'd mentioned taking a lot from
all the coaches that you've worked with
and you've already discussed having more
under center and things that are going
to deviate from what this offense has
been like the past two years. What's the
biggest thing that you learned from from
working with Cliff Kingsbury?
You know, I think uh it's hard to ignore
like how much stress you no huddle, you
know, the tempo element puts on a
defense and Cliff was incredibly
gracious to me just allowing me into his
brain of of how he thinks, how he sees
the game and what he has seen work. And
so, u, the last two years were
incredibly valuable for me to to see how
he, uh, how he approached game planning,
how he went about, you know, teaching
concepts and, um, he was incredibly
gracious. So, I'm I'm uh I'm really
thankful I got that experience with him
as a player and a coach.
>> Dave, just being only a couple years
removed from playing yourself, is there
an advantage at all, you think, when
especially when you're coaching a young
guy like Jaden to be so recently removed
from the game? I think a little bit. You
know, I think um you know, I've been
able to see it through his lens.
Definitely not at the you know, never
had the capabilities, the the ability
that he has. Um so I think, you know,
maybe there's a a a mutual respect for
what it takes to play quarterback in
this league. Um but and then I think
from now on it's what we DJ, Danny,
myself, what we do going forward to to
help grow him. um and and he'll see
quickly the value that we can add to his
game and and you know where we can get
this thing going in the right direction.
>> Hey, good afternoon, coach.
Congratulations.
>> Thank you.
>> Um we've gotten a small peak back in
your days in Detroit and how you support
your your wife. I I imagine some of that
support is at least given back to you as
well. Uh Nikki got to ask your
brother-in-law about his thoughts on
your getting promoted. Jaden has a very
tight familial bond as well that we all
know about. How important as a
quarterback in the NFL with so much of
what you do being publicized and
scrutinized and even criticized at
times, is it important to have that away
from the spotlight support system to
lean on?
>> It's everything, man. Like, um, when I
can walk out of here and go home and I
get to be dad and and husband to my
beautiful wife and dad to my daughter
and one on the way, it's like um, you
know, it's the why why you do things.
and um they Melissa's been the backbone
of our family, allowed me to sacrifice
so much as a player and then now
coaching, you know, it's no secret what
goes into that. And um you know, I
wouldn't be able to do it if she wasn't
just lifting me up just like the wind
beneath my sails. And um so I'm I'm
incredibly thankful she gets it having
been an athlete, you know, at the
highest level. And it's really special,
you know, this past weekend, even though
the game didn't go the way for the
Patriots, it was special for um, you
know, the way Christian played and uh,
really proud of him as well.
>> Have you had an opportunity to to speak
to coach Braum since you got promoted?
If so, how did that conversation go? you
know, we uh we stayed in contact really
over the last couple years as he knew I
wanted to get into coaching and so he
has always been in my corner and I I
learned a ton from coach Braum and uh he
really taught me just cornerstone
cornerstone foundations of you know what
quarterback play really was but uh
haven't communicated a whole lot since
but I'm sure we we will touch base soon.
Coach, congratulations and good
afternoon. From everything that you've
done already, from your time here to
your time playing in the league, etc.
Now that you've been elevated to this
position, what is it about you
specifically that's going to positively
impact this offense?
>> Um, I think I'm going to try to bring
out the best in everybody. I think uh
whether it's coaches or players, you
know, there's going to be standards set
with regard to excellence and um you
know, holding those guys to it. I think
I've been really fortunate, like I
mentioned a couple times, to see it done
at a really high level and understand
that you can't, you know, compromise on
the standards of excellence and and our
offense will be held to it. Our coaches
will be held to it and it's what I
expect from myself. And um you know,
it's a really fun opportunity to kind of
implement from the ground up what you
know, the the Washington Commanders
offense can look like in 2026.
>> David, first of all, congratulations. A
big opportunity for you. I know you've
developed a really good rapport and
relationship with Jaden over the last
couple of years. You've challenged him.
I'm curious, specifically Jaden, how's
he made you better? Maybe how has he
challenged you?
>> Yeah, I think um
I kind of mentioned it. He's got an
uncanny ability to just absorb anything
you share with him one time. So, the
challenge to that is, okay, how can we
stack on that the second time? What
where can we take his teaching and and
not assume that um you know, he's
already reached his capacity to learn?
How can we continue to build and take it
from, you know, when he first got here
in 2024, the 101 level classes and and
now, you know, how do we take him to
every time he takes the field Sunday,
uh, he's beaten people between his ears
and and at the highest level just um
able to put our offense in the best
position possible with his brain and and
I think that challenge of giving him new
content, new things to learn, new things
to understand about playing quarterback
in the NFL has been really stimulating
for for myself, for you know, the other
offensive coaches, uh, Brian Johnson, DJ
Williams, Danny, when we think about
what it can be for him, it's, you know,
how do we take him to that next level?
>> You've said the word conviction a couple
of times today, having a strong
conviction about this, strong conviction
about that. But sometime convictions
don't always play out the way you think
they'll play out during a game scenario.
So, being adaptable, being a first-time
NFL play caller. How will you kind of
navigate those challenges?
>> You know, I had a wise coach uh share,
you know, it's about strong convictions,
lightly held. And so, I think there's an
adaptability
um that we'll be fluid. We we're going
to do what our guys do best. Um there
will be staples of what our identity
will look like, but um you know there's
going to be some things that are easy
for us and hard for defenses. We're
going to make the same things look
different and different things look the
same and and you know teach in a
creative way and uh there's things that
I think will be really um evident when
they come to life you know on the field.
>> Congrats on the new gig. Um,
understandably a lot of talk about Jaden
here, but I'm curious, how do you feel
about the rest of this offense,
specifically your skill position
players?
>> Yeah, for sure. I, you know, right now
we've got, uh, 23 guys under contract on
the offense, and I feel really good
about it, man. I really do. Um, you
know, six in the wide receiver room,
returning Terry obviously at the at the
top of the group and, um, you know, it's
our opportunity. It's it's our challenge
to get the best out of every single guy
in the skill position groups and and up
front. Man, we we bring back so many
guys who played a ton of snaps on the
offensive line and the continuity there
is going to be key. And um you know, a
group that played really well last year.
And so as much as we can, it's it's
about the next, you know, 70 days for
our coaching staff, evaluating our own
players, acquiring new players, uh, to
figure out what we do best and then
implementing it so that, you know, 200
days from now when we take the field,
220 days from now when we take the field
that we have put in a ton of work um, to
put our guys in a position, teach what
they do really well, uh, to be at their
best, you know. you know, week one. So,
I I think we got a long way to go, but I
think it's it's going to be um a fun
construction process.
>> And then in the running back room, how
do you view Bill? Like, how much growth
potential is there? Or are you a firm
believer in kind of that committee
approach we saw with Cliff?
>> I think uh I think as everybody saw, you
know, all the flashes that Bill had in
his rookie season, I think it's really
exciting to think about what he can look
like in a second year behind this
offensive line. And I think um you know
we've got one running back sign so there
will defin definitely be acquisitions
that that take place there and um you
know depends exactly kind of how the the
room looks but man incredibly confident
in what Bill can be in this league as a
as a starting running back.
Hey David, for a um for a quarterback
that has played primarily in pistol and
shotgun through his college and NFL
career, what kind of challenges will
going under their center kind of
provide? And what does that what does
that kind of learning curve look like uh
for J?
>> You know, from like a a 30,000 foot
level, it's it's a you know, when we
teach quarterback play, not to dive too
far deep into it, it's it's simple
things of taking a sevenstep drop
instead of taking a fivestep drop or
taking a, you know, a seven step instead
of a three. And so there's a, you know,
just um basic fundamentals that go into
that. But um you know, even as the
course of the last couple weeks of the
season went on, he just he got more
experience at it with um a little bit of
a transition from our offense. Um you
know, with Josh playing at the end of
the year and even on, you know, when
there were scout team reps to be had
when we were working it, you know, this
has been a work in progress all the way
through. So it won't be completely new
to him. He's got a ton of time with
coaches, you know, that he's worked with
in California to to kind of grow in that
area and and we'll u you know, we'll hit
the ground running on that. Th
>> those last couple weeks when he was not
on IR but practicing but not not
playing, were you guys getting in work
along those lines? Were you starting to
kind of work on kind of specific things
with him that you kind of looked at
thought you can improve on?
>> You know, I think it it starts with with
any player in that situation. It's
growth areas. So that was one area we
saw for growth and um you know so as
much as we could we worked it for his
intentional development plan and I think
um you know we we saw it even in in the
four weeks at the end there that he
wasn't playing five weeks.
>> Hey David um congratulations.
>> Thank you.
>> Your when when people discuss this your
limited experience coaching comes up as
you might uh might have heard but you
also played quarterback unlike a lot of
the other offensive coordinators um in
the league. How does how do we translate
five years or so of playing quarterback
in the NFL to equals to how many years
of coaching?
>> I think it's a fair question. I think um
you know what I can kind of lean on is
whenever those conversations have
happened between the most important
relationship in my eyes, you know,
between the quarterback and the play
caller that I've seen take place, I've
gotten to be in the room for all those
conversations. you know, whether it was
Matthew in Detroit or Jared in Detroit
or Kirk in Minnesota or Kyler in Arizona
for a little bit, you know, it's like
you get to you get to be in the room
where all those conversations take place
and you hear how the coordinator thinks,
you hear, you know, so while you're not
um maybe calling the play in the huddle
as a backup like I was for the majority
of my career, you you get to you get
like you get let in the chess match, you
know, of of what uh a play caller is
thinking being on the headset. that
hearing the play call come in, the
dialect, the, you know, all the little
things that go into making a welloiled
machine kind of run.
>> And obviously you I'm sure you talked to
different people, your family, uh,
mentors, others about what whether to do
this, what do they think about this?
Ultimately, you have to decide what to
do. What was that final conversation
like with yourself of like I I don't
have to do this now. still got a long
way to go, but or hey, you never know
where those opportunities will come up
again.
>> I uh I think when these opportunities
come up with the, you know, with the men
that we have on this roster, with the
coaches that we have on the staff, with
Dan Quinn, Adam Peters, you have to go
for it. Um you know, I don't ever want
to live a life that is uh timid and so
we're going to go for it in a big way.
And it's really exciting to think about
um you know having this opportunity now
where I'm sitting and going forward and
just building it with the with the group
that we have.
>> Hey there. So you've been um here for a
bit now. You've experienced the high of
the high and a bit lower last year. So
what have you learned about this staff
and just being here um dealing with the
adversity that you all did last year?
Yeah, I think um you learn you learn a
ton on in both um both seasons, right?
you learn um
you know some of that perseverance you
know isn't always um about strength like
perseverance sometimes about direction
and and Dan Quinn has always uh been a
steady presence for us and he has just
pointed us in the right direction and
you see that through and through whether
it was 12 and five or five and 12 you
know so um his pouring into me I have
felt from the first day um just I have
felt that for me, but I've seen it for
every single member of our organization
and and that's something that you can't
overlook when when you make decisions
that you want to be a part of this and
and so that was really special. And then
and then I think on the coaching staff,
you learn, you know, in the hard days
that there's a lot of men uh in this
group that, you know, we can get in the
foxhole together and and we're going to
go battle it out and we're going to
treat each other with respect. we're
going to communicate at a high level and
and go and uh and really go after this
thing.
>> And there's um you know there's been
all-star games you know college all-star
games combine all the things. So what is
kind of like from now on I guess to
draft what are some of the important key
items on your list of things to do?
>> Sure. I think uh right now it's it's
digging into our own roster so that we
can evaluate for free agency in the
draft coming from the evaluation side uh
and give our feedback on what's going to
fit you know within our offense and then
uh you know with the offensive staff
it's it's building exactly what we want
this to look like come September. So
that's what the uh the work we're doing
daily is. Um you know, we finished, you
know, pretty close to finished staffing.
So, you know, now it's kind of
constructing exactly what we want the
offense to look like with regard to uh
concepts and formations and uh how we're
going to, you know, get after it.
>> Hi, coach. Uh congratulations on this
opportunity. You spoke early about your
development while being here. Where do
you feel that you've grown the most
being here?
It's a great question. I think um you
know as a player you come in Wednesday
morning and there's a game plan in front
of you that the coaches have prepared
and you have input in here or there but
you're a consumer as a player. Um now as
a coach on the other side you're a
teacher and we are creating content for
these men to um you know consume and we
have to creatively teach in a way that
will stick into their brain whether it's
uh through video clips or um PDFs or you
know different ways that we can
communicate with them how we articulate
exactly what we want to see come to life
and I think that's been the biggest
change for me over the two-year
uh two-year, you know, development
period is I have absolutely
uh loved seeing the teaching side of it.
Uh you know, after being a consumer for
so long
>> and you've seen this offense in and out,
what do you feel going into 2026 that
they need to grow the most?
You know, I think um you know, we'll
have an identity that I think you know,
people will see every every week when we
take the field, right? Like we're going
to do everything we can to be explosive,
take care of the ball and like be
creative and and our guys will uh you
know, you'll see kind of the DQ preaches
speed and violence and we want people to
feel that from our offense.
>> Congratulations, coach. A lot of talk
has been about your relationship with
Jaden, but how important is it to build
a balanced offensive attack where he
doesn't have to be super superman for
you guys to be successful?
>> Uh, very important. You know, like um I
talked about it. He's incredibly
accurate. He's mobility is a superpower
and um as we you know continue to use
his brain to you know our our offenses
uh benefit I think you'll see you know
as much as anything you'll see all these
skilled guys that we've talked about a
little bit um get unlocked and it's
going to be really uh special to see.
>> Thank you all.
>> I know
It's warm in here, too.